- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Watch this.
注意这个。
*
[slurping]
[发出声音]
[burps]
[打嗝]
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[both exclaim]
[两人惊呼]
- Mmm--hey.
- Hey.
- 嗯 - 嘿。
- 嘿。
[both repeating "Hey"]
[两人都重复着“嘿”]
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
Hiyah!
嗨！
Hiyah, hiyah!
嗨呀呀！
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- [screaming]
- Hiyah!
- [尖叫]
-嗨！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Aww.
哇。
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
*
Isn't it a little early
for autumn, Sandy?
是不是有点早了
秋天，桑迪？
- Yeah, it's only, um...
- 是的，这只是，嗯...
June o'clock.
六月了。
[munching]
[咀嚼]
- It ain't autumn.
- 这不是秋天。
[sniffs, gasps]
[吸气、喘气]
Oh, my tree is dying.
哦，我的树快死了。
[ax chops]
[斧头砍]
- Good, we can use the wood.
- 很好，我们可以用木头。
- Patrick, stop.
- 帕特里克，停下来。
I can save it with science.
我可以用科学拯救它。
- Okay.
Hmm.
- 好的。
唔。
[glass cracks]
[玻璃裂纹]
[sad music]
[悲伤的音乐]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
[monitor beeping]
[监视器蜂鸣声]
- Feed me.
- 喂我。
- Jumping beans on a trampoline.
- 在蹦床上跳豆子。
You're starving.
你快饿死了。
I got to make you
the best fertilizer
我必须让你
最好的肥料
known to critter-kind.
为小动物所熟知。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[yells]
[喊叫]
*
Ugh.
啊。
[choking]
[窒息]
[blows falling]
[击落]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Ah, growth pills.
啊，生长药。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
*
Hmm.
唔。
[gasps]
[喘气]
[fanfare]
[大张旗鼓]
Hey.
嘿。
[sad music]
[悲伤的音乐]
Nuts.
坚果。
*
Aha.
啊哈。
*
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
Yeehaw!
耶哈！
[humming cheerfully]
[欢快地哼唱]
Aw, I hope
this is the pick-me-up
噢，我希望
这是提神剂
you needed, ole girl.
你需要，老女孩。
[leaves rustling]
[树叶沙沙作响]
[exclaims]
[惊呼]
Well, kiss my grits.
好吧，亲吻我的玉米粒。
This here's the biggest acorn
I ever did see.
这是最大的橡子
我曾经见过。
[leaves rustling]
[树叶沙沙作响]
[acorns falling]
[橡子掉落]
And so are those.
那些也是如此。
I'd better start
storing these for winter.
我最好开始
把这些储存起来过冬。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
I might need
an alternate storage solution.
我可能需要
替代存储解决方案。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
*
Phew.
唷。
[gasps]
[喘气]
*
[buttons beeping]
[按钮发出蜂鸣声]
Hey there, SpongeBob.
嘿，海绵宝宝。
Could you swing by my place?
你能顺便过来一下我家吗？
*
I love squirreling away nuts,
我喜欢把坚果藏起来
but this is just too much.
但这实在是太多了。
- I'd say you've certainly
got a real nut-mare
- 我想说你肯定
有一个真正的疯子
on your hands.
在你的手上。
[blow falls]
[打击落下]
- Just dump these somewhere.
- 把这些扔到某个地方就可以了。
I'm gonna put more under my bed.
我要在床底下放更多东西。
- Yes, ma'am.
- 是的，女士。
*
[wheels squeaking]
[车轮吱吱作响]
[sighs]
[叹气]
- Stop!
- 停止！
- Whoa.
Who are you?
- 哇哦。
你是谁？
- I am the spirit guide
of the Salmon people.
- 我是精神导师
鲑鱼人的。
I am a shalmon.
我是一条鲑鱼。
- Oh, hey there, shalmon.
- 哦，嘿，沙蒙。
My name is SpongeBob.
我的名字是海绵宝宝。
- Why do you dump your nuts
- 为什么你要扔掉你的坚果
on my people's land, SpongeBob?
在我人民的土地上，海绵宝宝？
- Oh, they're not mine.
- 哦，他们不是我的。
They're my friend Sandy's.
他们是我朋友桑迪的。
- Allow me to give you
some sage advice.
- 请允许我给你
一些明智的建议。
You must not squander
nature's bounty.
你一定不能浪费
大自然的恩赐。
Nuts are meant to be eaten.
坚果是用来吃的。
It's all in my book.
这一切都在我的书中。
[flute music]
[长笛音乐]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Meant to be eaten, eh?
本来就是要吃的吧？
- Of course.
- 当然。
The earth provides our food,
地球为我们提供食物，
and we must care for her
in return.
我们必须照顾她
作为回报。
It's all about balance,
my friend.
一切都是为了平衡，
我的朋友。
Look at my garden.
看看我的花园。
*
- Wow.
It's coming in great.
- 哇。
一切进展顺利。
[jungle animals calling]
[丛林动物的叫声]
[stammering]
[结巴]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
Over there.
在那边。
[birds chirping]
[鸟鸣声]
- Even better.
- 甚至更好。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- So some shalmon guy
told you people would want
- 一些鲑鱼家伙
告诉你人们会想要
to eat my nuts,
and you believe him?
吃我的坚果，
你相信他吗？
- Uh-huh, uh-huh.
- 嗯嗯，嗯嗯。
Surely the shalmon
isn't a sham.
肯定是鲑鱼
不是假的。
- Shirtainly not.
- 绝对不是。
I mean, certainly not.
我的意思是，当然不是。
Let's see what we can cook up.
让我们看看我们能做什么。
"Aged nut brie,
“陈年坚果布里干酪，
ghost nut chili."
鬼坚果辣椒。”
How about nutty butter?
坚果黄油怎么样？
Seems easy enough to make.
看起来很容易制作。
*
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
*
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
*
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
That's delicious.
真好吃。
- Wow.
- 哇。
Patrick will want to try this.
帕特里克会想尝试一下。
- Try what?
- 尝试什么？
[both yell]
[两人大喊]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Patrick, that nutty butter
is for eating.
- 帕特里克，坚果黄油
是为了吃饭。
- I know.
- 我知道。
Ow!
噢！
Mmm.
嗯。
Ow!
噢！
Mmm.
嗯。
Ow!
噢！
- Hmm.
- 唔。
Why don't you boys take some
男孩们为什么不拿一些呢？
for the road?
为了道路？
both: Thanks.
两人：谢谢。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[knocking at door]
Huh?
[敲门]
啊？
- Can I have some more?
- 我可以再要一些吗？
It's hard to eat
off this side of me.
很难吃
在我的这一边。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Sure, Patrick.
- 当然，帕特里克。
Here's the last of it.
这是最后一个。
- Thanks, Sandy.
- 谢谢，桑迪。
*
- There, everything's back
to normal.
- 好了，一切都回来了
至正常。
crowd: We love nutty butter.
- What in tarnation?
人群：我们喜欢坚果黄油。
- 塔尼翁什么？
crowd: We love nutty butter.
We love nutty butter.
人群：我们喜欢坚果黄油。
我们喜欢坚果黄油。
We love nutty butter.
- Hi, Sandy.
我们喜欢坚果黄油。
- 嗨，桑迪。
- Patrick, what's going on here?
- 帕特里克，这是怎么回事？
- I want more nutty butter.
- 我想要更多坚果黄油。
- Who are all these people?
- 这些人都是谁？
crowd: We love nutty butter.
We love nutty butter.
人群：我们喜欢坚果黄油。
我们喜欢坚果黄油。
- Oh, they licked
the nutty butter off my back.
- 哦，他们舔了
我背上的坚果黄油。
*
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
And now they're here for more.
现在他们来这里是为了更多。
- Aw, gosh, Patrick,
- 噢，天哪，帕特里克，
I don't have enough
to feed everyone.
我没有足够的
养活每个人。
- But it's the only thing
my boy will eat.
- 但这是唯一的事情
我的儿子会吃。
- Guess I'll have to go to bed
hungry again.
- 我想我得去睡觉了
又饿了。
[all complaining]
[大家都在抱怨]
- Well, I don't want
to let anyone down.
- 好吧，我不想
让任何人失望。
I can make some more acorns.
我可以再做一些橡子。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
*
- [wailing]
- [哀号]
- Mmm.
- 嗯。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
*
- Making everyone's day
with my nutty butter
- 让每个人都开心
和我的坚果黄油
really gives me
the warm and tinglies.
真的给了我
温暖而刺痛。
- Uh-huh.
- 呃哈。
- In fact, demand's been
so high,
- 事实上，需求一直
这么高，
I scienced up a way
to increase my production.
我想出了一个科学方法
来增加我的产量。
[upbeat instrumental music]
[欢快的器乐]
SpongeBob here scoops acorns
onto the conveyor belt.
海绵宝宝在这里舀橡子
到传送带上。
Then the tubes take them inside,
然后管子把它们带进去，
where I turn them
into nutty butter.
我把它们转向哪里
变成坚果黄油。
*
- Sandy, according
to the shalmon's book,
- 桑迪，根据
到沙门的书里，
we shouldn't try to force nature
to give us more than she's able.
我们不应该试图强迫自然
给我们比她能力更多的东西。
- Don't worry about my tree,
SpongeBob.
- 别担心我的树
海绵宝宝。
Worry about the crowd
of nutty butter fans outside.
担心人群拥挤
外面的坚果黄油粉丝。
all: We want nutty butter.
We want nutty butter.
所有人：我们想要坚果黄油。
我们想要坚果黄油。
- We're gonna need
a lot more acorns
- 我们需要
还有更多的橡子
to feed them all.
养活他们所有人。
*
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
*
[leaves rustling]
[树叶沙沙作响]
*
- Uh-oh.
- 呃哦。
Sandy's tree's
not looking so good.
桑迪的树
看起来不太好。
I don't think it can take
much more of this, Patrick.
我认为这不能
还有更多这样的事情，帕特里克。
- Hmm.
- 唔。
It's like Sandy said.
就像桑迪说的那样。
"Something, something,
something, science."
“某事，某事，
一些东西，科学。”
And who are we to argue
with science?
我们该与谁争论
与科学？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
*
Oh, no.
哦，不。
The nuts stopped.
坚果停了下来。
- Hold on.
I got this.
- 坚持，稍等。
我明白了。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
Patrick, we have
to do something.
帕特里克，我们有
做某事。
Sandy'll never forgive us
if we ruin her tree.
桑迪永远不会原谅我们
如果我们毁了她的树。
- And I'll never forgive her
if she runs out of nutty butter.
- 我永远不会原谅她
如果她用完了坚果黄油。
- [exclaiming]
- [惊呼]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
*
- Please, please, no pushing.
- 拜托，拜托，不要催促。
I'll make more.
我会做更多。
Remember, Sandy's the squirrel
you can count on.
记住，桑迪是松鼠
您可以信赖。
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
*
What in the sam hill
is going on around here?
山姆山有什么
这附近有什么事吗？
- The tree got real sick.
- Don't worry.
- 这棵树病得很厉害。
- 不用担心。
I made more nutty butter
with the rest of the nuts.
我做了更多坚果黄油
和其余的坚果。
- You used all the nuts?
- 你用了所有的坚果吗？
Jumpin' jiminy.
跳跃吉米尼。
Time for another dose
of fertilizer.
是时候再服一剂了
肥料。
- Sandy, wait.
- 桑迪，等等。
I don't think that's what
your tree needs.
我不认为是这样
你的树需要。
- The boy is right.
- 这个男孩是对的。
Why do you hurt your tree?
你为什么要伤害你的树？
A tree would never hurt you.
一棵树永远不会伤害你。
Ouch!
哎哟!
Dang splinters.
当当碎片。
- Shalmon?
- 沙蒙？
- Wait, you're the one
who said
- 等等，你就是那个
谁说的
I should feed my nuts
to the people?
我应该喂我的坚果
对人民？
- Indeed.
- 的确。
But to feed so many
但养活这么多人
from a single tree...
从一棵树...
Let me share with you a story.
让我和你分享一个故事。
Long ago, before fish
walked the seas,
很久以前，在鱼之前
走过大海，
there lived in the sky
one sun.
天空中住着
一个太阳。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- One star.
- 一颗星。
- Hello.
- 你好。
- And one moon.
- 还有一个月亮。
- What the--
- 什么是--
- During the day,
- 白天，
the star would play
with the sun.
明星会演奏
与太阳。
At night, the star
晚上，星星
would play with the moon.
会和月亮一起玩。
- [giggling]
- Get away from me!
- [咯咯笑]
- 离我远点！
- The star did not want
to let his friends down,
- 明星不想
让他的朋友失望，
but he alone could not keep up
但他一个人跟不上
with both the sun
and the moon.
与两个太阳
和月亮。
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- Finally, some peace.
- 终于，平静了。
- That is when the star
had an idea.
- 那是明星的时候
有一个想法。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Huh?
Huh?
- 啊？
啊？
Oh, no.
- [giggling]
哦，不。
- [咯咯笑]
- There goes the neighborhood.
- 邻居走了。
- By creating many copies,
- 通过创建许多副本，
the star was able to keep
the sun and moon happy,
这位明星能够保留
太阳和月亮快乐，
without wearing himself out.
又不会让自己疲惫不堪。
Do you understand
why I tell you this tale?
你明白吗
我为什么要告诉你这个故事？
[all snoring]
[全都打呼噜]
- Hello?
Wake up.
- 你好？
醒来吧。
[all exclaim]
[所有人惊呼]
- I didn't know
there was gonna be a test.
- 我不知道
将会有一个测试。
- Oh, I got so wrapped up
in not letting anyone down
- 哦，我太着迷了
不让任何人失望
that I asked too much
of my tree...
我问得太多了
我的树...
and my friends.
和我的朋友们。
- Perhaps with many trees,
- 也许有很多树，
you could continue
serving your community
你可以继续
为您的社区服务
in a natural
and sustainable manner.
在自然的
和可持续的方式。
I mean, pretty much anything
is better than this mess.
我的意思是，几乎任何东西
总比这乱七八糟的好。
Yeesh.
是啊。
- Thanks, Shammy,
- 谢谢，沙米，
but I'm a one-tree
kind of squirrel.
但我是一棵独树
一种松鼠。
I'm gonna do what I should've
done in the first place:
我会做我应该做的事
首先完成：
order the ole girl
点了老女孩
some nutritious
new dirt from Texas.
一些有营养的
来自德克萨斯州的新泥土。
*
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- Well, my work here is done.
- 好了，我的工作已经完成了。
It's time
I return to my people.
是时候了
我回到我的人民身边。
*
Let me offer some sage advice.
让我提供一些明智的建议。
You must listen to the earth
and the stars,
你必须倾听大地的声音
和星星，
for only they can guide you...
因为只有他们才能引导你......
to my stop at the corner
of Olive and Victory.
到我在拐角处的车站
橄榄与胜利。
- Sir, stand behind
the white line, please.
- 先生，站在后面
请画白线。
- Typical.
It never ends.
- 典型的。
它永远不会结束。